Finding Aid for the Katherine Barnes Collection
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Katherine Barnes Collection
Undated
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0032
.42 linear feet
Biographical Note
Katherine Bowman Rolston Barnes was born in Lookout, Mountain Tennessee on August 17, 1914. She attended Vanderbilt University from 1931-1935 in the college of Arts of Sciences and was a very involved member of the academic community. While in school she was chairman of the Women’s Honor Committee and active in the Y.W.C.A., Kappa Alpha Theta sorority, as well the Scribblers, a women’s writing organization.
After she graduation she married fellow Nashvillian, Melville M. Barnes and continued her love of writings and poetry. Katherine was an active alumna of the Vanderbilt Community often participating in campus events. She wrote many articles for the Tennessee Historical Quarterly, the Nashville Banner, and the Christian Home among others. The first book she wrote, John Rosser: Gentleman of the Old South, was published in 1984.
She was died in Nashville, Tennessee on Friday March 7, 2003.
Scope and Content Note
The collection consists of one Hollinger box and is comprised of programs for theatre, ballet and musical performances she attended throughout her life. The collection is divided into three series: Playbills, Chicago Stage bills and Theatre and Ballet- Books
- Playbills
  - Playbills (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - “Abe Lincoln in Illinois” (1939)
    - “Born Yesterday” (1946)
    - “Brigadoon” (1947)
  - Playbills (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - “The boys from Syracuse” (1939)
    - “By George” (1967)
  - Playbills (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - “Carousel” (1946)
    - “Command Decision” (1947)
    - “The Consul” (1950)
  - Playbills (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - “Du Barry Was a Lady” (1940)
    - “Fiddler on the Roof”
    - “The Glass Menagerie” (1945)
  - Playbills (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - “Harvey” (1946)
    - “High Button Shoes” (1947)
    - “Hollywood Pinafore” (1945)
  - Playbills (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - “Kiss me Kate” (1950)
    - “The Late George Apley” (1945)
    - “Life with Father” (1940)
  - Playbills (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - “The Overtons” (1945)
    - “The Red Mill” (1946)
    - “Swan Song” (1946)
  - Playbills (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - The Voice of the Turtle” (1946)
    - “Yes, My Darling Daughter” (1937)
    - “1776”
- Chicago Playbills
  - Chicago Stage bill, - “Blossom Time” (1946) - “Dark of the Moon” (1946) - “The Joyous Season” (1946) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Chicago Stage bill, - “Kiss and Tell” (1944) - “Oklahoma” (2) - “The Mikado” (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Chicago Stage bill, - “St. Lazare’s Pharmacy” (1946) - “The Student Prince” (1944) - “Ten Little Indians” (1944) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Chicago Stage bill, - “Tropical Revue” (1944) - “Uncle Harry” (1944) - “You Can’t Take It with You” (1943) (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Theatre and Ballet -Books
  - Children in Blue and What They Do., 1907 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Memorabilia- Programs for Opera and Plays New York, (1938-1970) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Memorabilia- Programs for Opera and Plays Nashville and Birmingham (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Ballets Jooss. 4th Season., 1933-1937 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Col. W. de Basil’s Ballet’s Russes. 4th Season., 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - The Lost Colony. 360th anniversary edition., 1587-1947 (Box 1, Folder 18)